<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-04-12T21:21:18-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">L5</title><subtitle>The orbital board game</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Life in L5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life-in-l5" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life in L5" /><published>2017-08-01T06:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-01T06:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life-in-l5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life-in-l5">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The responsibility of supporting human life in space is shared between five highly specialized Careers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Citizens of the Orbit who dedicate their lives to humanity’s preservation spend years at L1 training at the Five Academies. Their formal education ends when they sign the Constitution and choose a single &lt;strong&gt;Career&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Culture&lt;/strong&gt; to place in the center of their life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The five Careers, together, support life in space by each taking responsibility for one of the five necessities: &lt;strong&gt;Water&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Atmosphere&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Habitat&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Gravity&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/team-bw.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Five Careers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ASTRONAUTS&lt;/strong&gt; schedule the rotations of the arcades and the flow of shuttles between them to keep the whole station spinning together as a giant clock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Role: The Astronaut leads the team and keeps them on task and on schedule with their trusty Compass and Drive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DIVAS&lt;/strong&gt; keep their communities hydrated and relaxed by brewing teas and drawing baths with the finest imported ices harvested from distant asteroids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Role: Mostly self-sufficient, the Diva always has a trick up their sleeve to help the team get unstuck.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRODUCERS&lt;/strong&gt; design and print the station’s massive habitation structures - the serpentine Arcades, the central Keep, and the protective Shade enclosing the station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Role: The Producer is very mobile and can travel easily from arcade to arcade with a Backpack full of useful, customized data.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CLERICS&lt;/strong&gt; keep the station anchored to its spot in relation to other distant stations by constantly updating their exact location and publishing it to their cultural Feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Role: Slow and always absorbed in their Feed, the Cleric makes up for their antisocial attitude with the ability to create and store an enormous volume of data.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROGRAMMERS&lt;/strong&gt; control the weather - they program drafts, currents, and storms of the origami data drones that circulate the station’s vents and keep the air in motion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Role: The Programmer keep the team connected by controlling the flow of information.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Noah Mease</name></author><category term="World of L5" /><summary type="html">The responsibility of supporting human life in space is shared between five highly specialized Careers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Windows through Time</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/windows-through-history" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Windows through Time" /><published>2017-07-30T06:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-30T06:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/windows-through-history</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/windows-through-history">&lt;p&gt;Living in space without windows is pretty intolerable. Windows keep everyone oriented. They provide a sense of scale. The bigger the vista the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest windows (usually just called “a window”) are communial spaces. Much like a village green or a prehistoric fire circle, they are the focal point around which orbital society is organized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stations in L5 have five different kinds of these windows. Each varriety has its own function and customs, and each appeared at a different time in the history of the orbit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/window_icon_sketch.png&quot; alt=&quot;window icons&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;observatory&quot;&gt;Observatory&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/observatory_sketch.png&quot; alt=&quot;observatory sketch&quot; /&gt;
The observatory was the first window to be recognized as a distinct and necessary feature of a space station. Even in the early days of orbital development when RedCorp was building its first commerical habitats, the importance of windows to sustainable space habitation was well known. All permanently enhabitated stations were required by the astronauts to have at least one observatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, the observatory became the place that astronauts would meet to coordinate their work, plan projects, and make decisions. As the seat of municipal power and cultural administration, they continue to have a similar function today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ampitheater&quot;&gt;Ampitheater&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/ampitheater_sketch.png&quot; alt=&quot;ampitheater sketch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;server&quot;&gt;Server&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/server_sketch.png&quot; alt=&quot;server sketch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;garage&quot;&gt;Garage&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/garage_sketch.png&quot; alt=&quot;garage sketch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;studio&quot;&gt;Studio&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/studio_sketch.png&quot; alt=&quot;studio sketch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bill Noble</name></author><category term="World of L5" /><summary type="html">Living in space without windows is pretty intolerable. Windows keep everyone oriented. They provide a sense of scale. The bigger the vista the better.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to L5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/welcome" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to L5" /><published>2017-07-27T06:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T06:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/welcome">&lt;p&gt;HELLO, WORLD!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re making a board game called L5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how we’re describing it right now — but this description has been through many wild rewrites over this past year of development, so don’t hold us to any of it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;L5 is a cooperative role-playing strategy game where you and your friends become a team of experts trying to prevent giant space stations from breaking apart. With unique skill sets, specialized tech, and a stacked deck of talents, you’ll overcome personal crises, unlock hidden files, and confront the station’s super-powered leadership to keep everything hanging together in a stable orbit. While playing through each station, you’ll ask questions and gather clues about the wider world of L5… hints which may lead you past the edges of Orbital Society to the lonely places where Legends live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to make a game that’s quick and fun to play for folks who’ve always been into the &lt;em&gt;idea&lt;/em&gt; of a full-blown role-playing tabletop game but who can’t quite get it together to read a book of rules or do much story prep ahead of time. Playing through each station for the first time should feel like an episodic entry into an endless L5 saga – a series of 45- to 90-minute puzzle-mazes that leads you deeper into the darker lore hidden within this whimsical far-future civilization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll collect and roll dice, build decks of talent cards, and explore an evolving game board to unlock top-secret information about the world around you as you prepare to face the station’s Super in a test of strategy, luck, and memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure you have a lot of questions. So do we.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we want this site to be the place to ask them. This is a place where we’ll post updates about the lore of the world we’re building, track highlights from our development process, and publish a downloadable, DIY version of the game as we make it so you can play along at home and tell us what’s cool and what’s broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;3 Bill &amp;amp; Noah&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, yeah… and check out the ABOUT page for more info on who “we” are.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Noah Mease</name></author><category term="Announcements" /><summary type="html">HELLO, WORLD! We’re making a board game called L5. Here’s how we’re describing it right now — but this description has been through many wild rewrites over this past year of development, so don’t hold us to any of it: L5 is a cooperative role-playing strategy game where you and your friends become a team of experts trying to prevent giant space stations from breaking apart. With unique skill sets, specialized tech, and a stacked deck of talents, you’ll overcome personal crises, unlock hidden files, and confront the station’s super-powered leadership to keep everything hanging together in a stable orbit. While playing through each station, you’ll ask questions and gather clues about the wider world of L5… hints which may lead you past the edges of Orbital Society to the lonely places where Legends live. We want to make a game that’s quick and fun to play for folks who’ve always been into the idea of a full-blown role-playing tabletop game but who can’t quite get it together to read a book of rules or do much story prep ahead of time. Playing through each station for the first time should feel like an episodic entry into an endless L5 saga – a series of 45- to 90-minute puzzle-mazes that leads you deeper into the darker lore hidden within this whimsical far-future civilization. You’ll collect and roll dice, build decks of talent cards, and explore an evolving game board to unlock top-secret information about the world around you as you prepare to face the station’s Super in a test of strategy, luck, and memory. I’m sure you have a lot of questions. So do we. And we want this site to be the place to ask them. This is a place where we’ll post updates about the lore of the world we’re building, track highlights from our development process, and publish a downloadable, DIY version of the game as we make it so you can play along at home and tell us what’s cool and what’s broken. &amp;lt;3 Bill &amp;amp; Noah</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The World of L5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/world-of-l5" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The World of L5" /><published>2017-07-27T06:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T06:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/world-of-l5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/world-of-l5">&lt;p&gt;L5 is set in the future, when we live in space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Earth&lt;/strong&gt; is uninhabitable - the High Seas have covered all but the tallest mountain peaks, and enormous storm systems torment the atmosphere. &lt;strong&gt;The Moon&lt;/strong&gt; has been mined to swiss cheese and it’s thin atmosphere offers little protection from the constant barrage of meteorites, which often cause massive cave-ins deep inside the brittle satellite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But humanity persists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though some have found a way to survive the harsh conditions of life on Earth or on it’s barren satellite, most people live in giant swirling space stations parked in &lt;strong&gt;the LaGrange Points&lt;/strong&gt; - five islands of stable orbit created by the wake of the Moon’s gravity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/l5-logo-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Earth-Moon system&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L5&lt;/strong&gt; is the most populous L-Point and the heart of Orbital Society, where a rainbow of different cultures coexist in chaotic harmony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L4&lt;/strong&gt; is the seat of multifaceted, opulent Tārā culture and the launch point for luxurious mining cruisers headed out to the Asteroid Belt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L3&lt;/strong&gt; is the most remote L-Point and, as maintained by Gaia aid workers, remains the last point of contact with the humans who choose to stay on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L2&lt;/strong&gt;, beyond the Moon, is the site of BlueCorp’s information monasteries — their powerful interstellar arrays endlessly scanning the universe for signs of other intelligent life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L1&lt;/strong&gt; contains the ruins of a space elevator, which, in ancient times, was the main artery between Earth and the Orbit. The ruins now house the Constitution, the living document that unites the five Cultures together as an Orbital Society.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Noah Mease</name></author><category term="World of L5" /><summary type="html">L5 is set in the future, when we live in space. The Earth is uninhabitable - the High Seas have covered all but the tallest mountain peaks, and enormous storm systems torment the atmosphere. The Moon has been mined to swiss cheese and it’s thin atmosphere offers little protection from the constant barrage of meteorites, which often cause massive cave-ins deep inside the brittle satellite.</summary></entry></feed>